251 10th St. NW, C509 Atlanta, GA 30318 U.S.A.

# ChangSeok Oh

Profile: https://shivamidow.github.io E-mail: changseok@gnome.org Mobile: +1 (404) 740-7896

Open source enthusiast and hacker specializing in web technology and linux-based systems. A WebKit and GNOME project contributor. More than 8 years experience at major players in the industry. Looking for opportunities in Web browser, Web Security & Privacy, Kernel, and Computer Graphics.

Skills

WebKit, Blink/Chromium, GNOME, Linux, C/C++, Python, HTML/CSS/Javascript, Objective-C, Java, OpenGL/OpenGL ES, Clutter, Computer Graphics, GTK+, eBPF, BCC, Ethereum, Git, OBS, Clang, LLVM, GStreamer, Tizen, Linux Perf, Bluetooth LE, ReactJS, React Native, Embedded system, Puppeteer

## Education

08/2017 - present 08/2017 - 08/2019 03/2000 - 06/2008 Ph.D student (advisor: Prof. Wenke Lee) in Computer Science, Georgia Tech in Atlanta, GA, U.S.A. M.S. in Computer Science (Computer Systems, GPA: 3.87 / 4.0), Georgia Tech in Atlanta, GA, U.S.A. Dual B.E. in Digital Media and Computer Engineering, Ajou University, South Korea

## Professional Experience

06/2019 - present Intern at Igalia, S.L. in A Coruña, Spain • Bring ANGLE backend for WebGL to WebKitGTK • Zero copy texture sharing between Mesa and ANGLE via Linux DMA buffer 05/2020 - 08/2020 Intern at Samsung Research America in Mountain View, CA 05/2019 - 08/2019 • Build a web app for health data analysis with ReactJS (frontend) and Node.js (backend) • Built an automated system that verifies UI of a watch app by using Tizen automation framework Profiled memory usage and revealed possible memory leak of a watch app by using Valgrind • Implemented file transfer via Bluetooth LE in an React Native watch application Software engineer at Collabora Ltd. in Cambridge, UK 08/2012 - 03/2016 • Developed hardware based compositing based on Clutter in WebKit • Resource efficient web browser based on GNOME Epiphany for Raspberry Pi 2+ • Customized WebKit features and API set for Smart TV Alliance SDK 07/2008 - 08/2012 Assistant Software engineer at Samsung Electronics in Suwon, South Korea • Developed an in-house web layout engine for Smart TVs, Printers in C++ • Implemented WebGL and Accelerated Compositing in WebKit EFL by using OpenGL ES for Tizen Intern at Samsung Software Membership in Suwon, South Korea 07/2007 - 06/2008 • Developed a 3D racing game using DirectX on Windows (video)

# Academic Experience

08/2017 - 08/2019

#### Research assistant at School of Computer Science, Georgia Tech

- Redesign chromium to block user tracking with web browser fingerprints
- Debloat chrome browser with feature sunsetting on the fly by binary rewriting
- Developed a defense system against micro DDoS by profiling resources with HPC (Intel PCM, MBM)
- Implemented an idle profiler that diagnoses off-cpu time in multi-threaded program using HPC

08/2019 - present

#### Teaching assistant at School of Computer Science, Georgia Tech

• CS 6262: Network Security, Design and Implement the XSS task using node.js and Chrome Extension

#### **Open Source Projects**

04/2013 - present

- Committer at WebKit (patches) • Implement Gamepad API with libmanette
- Implement AVIF image decoder with dav1d
- Implemented OpenGL ES backend for Accelerated Compositing.
- Developed memory pressure handler that copes with out-of-memory on top of Linux cgroup.
- Enhance WebGL support and Fix layout and rendering issues
- Fix CVE security bugs in WebKit (CVE-2020-10018, CVE-2020-11793)

10/2013 - present

**Member at GNOME foundation** (patches)

• Translate GNOME Web and its Help document in Korean

01/2015 - present

## Contributor at Chromium/Blink (patches)

• Implemented a CSS spec called font-size-adjust • Fix layout and rendering issues in blink

#### **Publication**

CCS 2020 Slimium: Debloating the Chromium Browser with Feature Subsetting (To Appear)

By Chenxiong Qian, HyungJoon Koo, ChangSeok Oh, Taesoo Kim, Wenke Lee

# **Patents**

US 20110296323 US 20110289110 Web page management method and apparatus and storage medium thereof Method of re-searching webpage and apparatus and storage medium therefor US 20110093606 Interface method and display device Interface method and display device

Presentations

12/07/2014 Web Engines Hackfest 2014 in A Coruña, Spain (slides)
09/29/2014 DEVIEW 2014 in Seoul, South Korea (slides, video)
Jeju University in Jeju, South Korea (slides)
DevOn 2013 in Seoul, South Korea (slides)

*Last update : 07/29/2020*